We have a short 4 hours together. This
is my favorite format of working
together. I have whiteboard.
I have markers. I'm a happy boy.
The way this works is I have some
slides.
But the slides are only here as a visual
aid to what we're doing. I want to begin
this masterclass by delving into the
problems, the challenges that you're
facing, cuz this is all about you. I've
been talking to so many of you guys the
last couple of days that I want to make
sure you leave this event with no FOMO.
You've not missed anything. Yeah? Is
that okay?
>> [cheering]
>> All right.
We can do this together. So, what I want
to do is I want you to really think
about the problem because most
presenters, when you ask a question,
they just go into answer mode. So, you
feel like you have this one shot to
package all the information, but I'm not
most presenters. See, I have a dialogue
with you. So, give me a little and we
start to dialogue. We're in rapport and
we'll show you how this is done. I
really want you to think about the
problem cuz that's all I listen to.
We'll start with you guys. Can we get
the mic runners here? By the way, before
we get started, I just want to say can
we just give it up for the mic runners,
please, everybody? It's a difficult job.
Difficult job. Somebody give them the
mic.
>> [applause]
>> Give give them a mic. And then also the
AV team, the audio team, the video team,
they've been amazing to work with. You
guys are amazing. Thank you.
>> So, we have a product in travel
business.
And we are focusing a lot on experience.
But how can you brand this experience in
a world where there is so much noise and
everyone is trying to cover their
products in experience, you know? Like
make them look like everything is
experience, you know? Like
>> Okay, let's slow down. The way you begin
this is I want you to put on your your
best trailer voice. In a world of
experience design.
Okay, and then you ask the question.
Go ahead.
>> So, in a world full of
>> [laughter]
>> noise. That's pretty good.
Would you watch that movie?
Give it a little more gravitas, bro.
Use your chest voice. Let's go. In a
world Give me some bass there.
>> full of experience and noise, how can we
make the most of our actual plan?
>> [laughter]
>> He's really good, guys.
I don't know what he has, but he's
really good. First of all, hey, yeah,
give me a give me a fist bump here. That
was really good. You guys look Okay,
this is the example. We play. We're
going to play together. Somebody might
get hurt, more you than me, but somebody
might get hurt. That's okay. It's always
funny for everyone except for that
person. Okay, I don't understand the
conflict. You say it's a very noisy
world.
>> Yes.
>> Okay, so I'll write the word noisy. Now,
what else? What else do I need to know?
>> You need to know that we are focusing on
experience. That's basically becoming
the product.
>> Okay, and you're in travel, right?
>> Yes, in travel business, yeah.
>> What kind of travel?
>> Uh well, we are taking people to
adventures like in Iceland or in
destinations that are different that
what they usually do. Yeah, and we do it
like with small groups, so the
experience is like more customized.
>> Okay, high-end bespoke.
>> Yeah, somewhat, but we try to keep the
price low, so we make people come back.
We have like a 90% rate of retention,
for example.
>> What's your price?
Roughly?
>> Like four
Like 2,000 euros, like I would say.
>> That's great. How many days?
>> Like you get like seven to 10 days.
>> Wow. Chris, we got to take a trip.
I think this is a sales pitch for this
room.
>> [laughter]
>> This is a fake question, I believe.
Okay, seven to 10 days for 2K. That's
fantastic.
>> Yeah.
>> You good at doing this?
>> Yeah, actually we are really good.
>> Can you make money doing this?
>> Uh yes, we got to seven figures this
year after five years.
>> Wow. Well, first of all,
congratulations.
>> Yeah, thanks.
>> Seven figures
euro, not roan,
>> Uh yeah.
>> Oh yeah, okay. Just double checking
here. You know what? We should talk
later.
I I want to do experience travel for
people to travel with me. This is an
excellent price. We'll charge 8K. We'll
pay you the two.
>> Yeah, no worries. Yeah.
>> You're good, right? You're happy? No,
this is real. I'm not kidding around.
>> Yeah.
>> Will you connect with Drigo, my
right-hand guy?
>> Yeah, sure.
>> For real? Okay. So, what's your problem
now?
>> So,
>> [laughter]
>> my problem is that I want to show people
that we are doing things differently.
>> Okay.
>> But, there is so much hypocrisy I see.
>> Oh yeah, okay. What's that? Okay.
There's a mindset thing here.
>> Yeah.
>> We have to be very mindful of how we use
words. He's like, "So much noise,
hypocrisy."
Is anybody excited to work in that
space?
No.
So, what we want to do Krishnamurti said
this, "The highest form of intelligence
is to observe without judgment."
>> Yeah.
>> So, words that are judging that assign
value to things like noisy
>> Mhm.
>> and hypocrisy, that's very violent
language to describe something.
>> Yeah.
>> If you show up every single day and say,
"I hate my job. I hate my clients. I
hate my life." Guess what? You're going
to be really miserable.
Uh people backstage a little concerned
for me like, "How you doing?"
I said, "Excellent.
Best day of my life."
And I mean that. I am just glad
I'm alive.
And I have an opportunity to speak to so
many of you, right?
Yeah. It could be because there's a lot
of sunshine in California. So, I'm just
happy. A lot of rain and clouds here.
But, let's just change our disposition
on this a little bit, okay? We have a
problem. We just want to solve the
problem. Strip away all the emotional
language here. And please pay attention,
everybody, cuz we're going to do this
for the next 4 hours. Let's not have me
repeat this over and over again. Drigo,
am I doing okay?
>> You're doing great, Chris.
>> Great.
When I need your help, will you be
ready?
Perfect.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay. So, you just need to show the
experience. Yes?
>> Exactly. I want to show
>> you tried?
>> Well, we've tried to show a little bit
behind the scenes.
>> Wow.
>> And all the photos and videos
>> Yeah, and all the content we have on the
website, all the photos are actually
made by us. We don't use any stock or
something.
>> Well, I wouldn't brag too much about
that, but okay.
>> Well, I'm just saying that we are trying
>> use AI or stock. It's okay.
>> No, I'm just saying we show the whole
process. Yeah.
>> Okay. Are they really sexy images and
videos? People doing like exciting
amazing things?
>> Uh
somehow.
>> See, somehow I don't believe you now.
Like somehow I don't believe Drigo
saying nice things about me.
>> Well, we try to put the perspective like
if you were there with your eyes, like
POV perspective in the areas we show.
>> That's not the question I asked.
>> Okay.
>> It's like I ask like say, are you
married?
>> Uh yeah.
>> Uh say I'm your wife and like, where
were you? And you're like, I had drinks.
Where were you? You're not answering the
same question. We have to be on the same
wavelength here. You got it? Let's stay
married for a long time. Yes?
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, that's a good thing, right?
I've heard some rumors, but okay. Oh,
we'll talk about that later. So, the
videos have to be so exciting that I
just want to book it now.
Cuz I tell you right now, based on my
experience, this is a very compelling
price.
>> Yeah.
>> Drigo, we were just in Japan last year.
How much did we charge for people to
travel with us for 6 days?
>> $7,500.
>> That is a bargain.
>> flights
>> a bargain.
>> is. I know. I know we have
>> So, this is one of those things where in
my experience, this is a bargain. It's
an offer so good that I should be stupid
to say no to. Fantastic job on that. So,
all you have to do, in my opinion, is to
show people the experience that you say
you're giving them.
>> Yes, that's the hard thing.
>> No, because you can hire people to do
that. Are you a cinematographer, editor?
>> Mm, no. I'm basically a graphic designer
turned brand strategist.
>> The answer is no. Just say no. That's
fine.
>> So, what we do is we try to do too much
ourselves, and so then the work doesn't
look right. And I I tell you something,
historically speaking, we are the worst
judge of our own value. Everybody feel
this? We are the last one to say we're
worth something.
>> Yes.
>> Right? So, when you have someone with
fresh eyes who can look at you
objectively like me and say, "This is a
bargain. This is amazing. If you can
deliver a great experience." Now I need
proof. Guess where the proof is.
Where's the proof, my friend?
>> Well, in the actual product, right? When
you come with us
>> No, it's too late. I need to see the
proof.
>> So, then in the content.
>> Be more specific.
>> Pictures, videos, right?
>> Yes. These things that are not stock.
>> The content
>> need to see great photos and videos, and
we need to see testimonials.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> We need to see it written, and we need
to see it in video form. We need to see
people having the best time of their
lives.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay?
>> don't have a lot of that.
>> So, here's the problem, and this is what
everybody here has.
Human beings have an imagination gap. We
cannot imagine things the way that you
see things. Okay? For example, there was
a time which I did not do brand strategy
at all. But it was really clear I could
do this. But I didn't have proof. So,
every time I asked a client, "Would you
like to hire us to do brand strategy for
30K?" they would say, "No." Because
there's an imagination gap. I had to
close the gap. How do we close the gap?
We agreed to do a project for less money
than we would. So, then now I have
proof. I show that proof, and now people
say, "Yes."
So, you just have to document the proof
of people having an amazing experience
in all forms of media. Photos, videos,
illustrations, testimonials, audio,
everything that you can think of, you
share.
>> Okay.
>> Okay? Now, I imagine you're sharing this
on your website.
>> Oh, yeah, and mostly social media.
>> What what platform?
>> On Instagram mostly.
>> Okay. Lot of views?
>> Uh yeah.
>> How What's the How big is your
following?
>> Well, I don't remember exactly. Like
>> So suspicious.
This is the guy his name is Morgan Jay.
Do you guys know the comedian Morgan
Jay? He's the auto-tuned comedian and he
sings a song suspicious as
>> [laughter]
>> You know the words.
>> I don't know. I think it's like around
10K or something like
>> Okay. Are you ashamed of that or are you
proud of that?
>> Well, I mean I don't know what to think
about it.
>> Doesn't feel like he's that proud of it.
10K is not that easy to get these days.
>> Yeah, I know, but like I feel we are so
much more
>> 10K, bro.
>> We are so much more.
>> Okay, there's a lot of work. You know
the cool thing is
these kinds of videos with a strong
emotional hook are highly watchable.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Let's get into content marketing,
everybody, okay? Now, many of you are
using social and you're probably using
it the wrong way.
So, if you just use this as a
promotional video, no one will watch it
cuz we know it's a commercial. We know
this, but we keep doing things like
this. What we want to do is to show a
story. It's called the before-and-after
story.
Okay? Before and after.
Okay?
Do you know what that means?
>> Well, I I can guess.
>> You can guess? Okay, well, let's test
your guessing.
What are we going to show before and
after?
>> Well,
it's before you go into I I mean before
you experience like our product
or what?
>> Well,
you're running out of enthusiasm.
>> No, I'm just I'm I'm I'm going into
thinking mode now and I'm
>> Okay. Brain processing.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> It's the beach ball on the mic.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, okay. The before-and-after is we
want to see great change. We want to see
an arc.
>> Okay.
>> Okay, so I'll draw a red marker here. We
want to see this arc. How were we
before? How are we after? How we
transformed by that experience? So, you
can interview some some timid people who
talk about like, "I've never left my
country. The farthest I've ever traveled
is 200 mi away from home, and I I drove
in a car. I'm afraid of flying. I'm
afraid of spiders. I don't like ice. I'm
not good with cold weather."
>> Okay, yeah.
>> Okay? And you build up the tension. So,
like what's going to happen to this
person? And then you you drop them into
the ice, and they're like drowning, and
then they're climbing an ice mountain.
You see now that story, those visuals
have a lot more weight because I set up
the story. Drigo, you've mastered this.
>> Yes.
>> Tell me a time when you had a story that
you needed to work on and how you found
that contrasting point. We talked about
this recently.
>> I think the recent story for me was the
filming at the airport where I wasn't
really sure how to tell that story and
how to tap back in and into a moment
when I was
>> [snorts]
>> younger.
>> Which story was this?
>> The airport one.
>> You got to set it up so the audience
knows.
>> You know, I wasn't ready for that
question, Chris, so
>> It's pretty easy to be up here, yeah?
>> It's a little bit harder than you make
it look sometimes.
>> Okay, okay. So, does everybody have this
thing here? So, what we do is we like to
tell the story looking forward, like how
things are great. And if we do that,
that's totally okay.
And we often forget like there's
something that happened previously that
sets up the meaning of the story. I'm on
a request for love, for adventure. I've
always been told I can't do this. I'll
never accomplish this. And then we get
to go again. Watch this, okay? There's a
Let's say there's a Navy SEAL. Okay? And
they're super athletic. They can do
everything, and they have this
reputation as badasses. Not only are
they strong, they're tough, and they're
smart.
They can do everything.
Pretty boring story.
Right? But let's say that you're like
undersized, picked on all your life, and
you experience a car crash when you're
young,
and you were in a coma for 7 days.
And you got out of it, and you asked
yourself, "What's the meaning of my
life?" And you started to exercise, and
you got fit. And you decided to take on
the biggest challenge of life. And
that's how I became a Navy SEAL. See the
difference there?
>> Yeah.
>> So, what we do is we pull those points
apart, the past and the present and the
future, and we find that one node, cuz
there's a million nodes that make that
story more dramatic, more interesting,
and set up the motivation for why we do
what we do.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you have a very common problem. I do
something cool
at an affordable price. Everyone should
say yes to. So, you've done the hard
work.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay?
>> Yeah, I'm doing good.
>> The The next part is you have to be a
better storyteller.
And I have some slides for that. So,
I'll show you, okay?
Thanks, Drigo.
>> All right, bro.
>> Round of applause for Drigo, everybody.
>> [cheering and applause]
>> Okay. I I only have like 67 slides here.
So, let me find the one that's right.
Okay, here we go. Story formula. Can we
see this?
Yeah, okay, cool. All right. There's a
story formula. I used to teach
sequential design for almost 15 years at
Art Center.
And as far as I can tell, I've taken the
most complicated structures. I did not
invent this, but I just made it simpler.
That's my job, to make complicated
things simpler. So, it looks like this.
Okay? Every story has these three
components. And you just need to
remember this is easy easy that I
actually taught my children this when
they're 5 years old. There's a
character, and they want something.
Something stands in their way.
There's a character, they want
something, and something stands in their
way. Notice the way I set up today's
workshop with you is what is it you
want, and what's standing in your way.
It's called an obstacle or a challenge.
Something's holding you back. Often
times, we think it's a physical thing,
but most of the times, it's a mindset
thing. Okay? Without the obstacle, there
is no story. Robert McKee, who wrote the
book called Story. He teaches and
consults with Hollywood screenwriters.
No conflict, no story.
Somebody wants something and can't get
it, right? So, the classic love story is
boy falls in love with girl, boy can't
get girl because
that's the beginning of the story.
Because why? Because their families hate
each other.
That's Romeo and Juliet. Right? Uh boy
falls in love with girl, but can't get
girl. Why? Because he's rich and she's a
maid. That's Maid in Manhattan. Boy
falls in love with girl, can't get girl.
Why? Cuz she's a prostitute and he's a
rich dude.
This is story like it's the same
freaking story over and over again,
right?
Uh
cuz boy is um owns the giant mega
bookstore and woman owns a small
independent bookstore.
That's You've Got Mail.
It happens over and over again. And when
we deviate from the formula,
those movies don't perform.
I used to go to art school and the cool
thing at art school was to go to art
house movies. Experimental art, you
know, French avant-garde, unwatchable.
But I had to pretend like, "Oh my god,
that's so amazing." So, I like, "What
happened?" I don't know. They just ended
the movie. She dropped the donut and it
was done. I'm like, "What?" That's why
they're not popular anymore, okay? You
just need to know the formula. So, what
happens then is we hit the obstacle
and instead of getting what we want, we
get what we need. Oftentimes what we
want is something external and what we
need is something internal, okay?
Uh boy wants girl, can't get girl cuz
boy's nerd, girl's cheerleader. Happens
all the time, right? And what he does is
he has money, instead of buying the
instrument like a flute or a saxophone,
he uses the money to say, "Hey, can you
pretend to like me? I'll be really
popular in high school." And then all of
a sudden people start to like him. And
then the girl actually has real
feelings. She catches feelings for him,
right?
But he becomes a jerk.
Cuz he's like, "Now I'm popular. Girl, I
don't need you."
So, what he thought he wanted was to be
popular. What he needed to do was to be
confident and to learn that he is
enough.
Make sense?
>> Yeah, it's
>> There's a want and then there's a need.
So, at the end of the story, the
character is transformed.
So, character want, obstacle, instead of
getting what you want, you get what you
need, and you're left transformed. That
transformation is what makes us
emotionally engage with the story.
Everybody understand? Without that
transformation, we're like really angry.
Like, "Why won't you learn the lesson?"
Okay.
Have you guys seen the movie Whale
Rider?
It's a really old film. I think it's
from New Zealand. It's a beautiful film.
I watched it and I like cried like a
baby.
I don't even cry.
It was internal tears.
But the story was
the father
thought this small village was too small
for him. So, he went to the city. So, he
abandoned his girl
because he's out there trying to make
money.
And the grandfather became bitter that
the boy left and betrayed the village.
And because she was the only child of
this this man,
>> [clears throat]
>> he thought she was an omen for the
village. So, whenever they couldn't
catch fish, when when things were going
bad, the grandfather would blame her.
And now I'm sitting there so mad. Like,
"What does little girl ever do to you?"
And she works so hard to prove herself
against all the boys. They're on the
water and they would dive for pearls, I
believe. And she could hold her breath
longer than everyone. She would find
everything and she would risk her life
all the time just to prove that she's as
good as the boys. But no matter what she
did, her grandfather never loved her.
And it was heartbreaking. I mean, I'm
just getting choked up thinking about it
right now. Okay?
So, one day there's there's a whale that
beaches itself on on the shore and it's
not a good sign.
Not a good sign.
And so, they don't know what to do.
They're like praying, they're they're
doing all the kinds of things they can
do. She decides to go out and touch the
whale. And for whatever reason in the
story, she climbs on top of the whale
and she holds onto the whale.
For whatever reason, movie magic, the
whale wakes up and it starts to swim out
into the ocean.
So, she saves the whale. In the process,
all the villagers are going crazy.
They're running after her and they're
like, "Let go of the whale." And she
won't let go of the whale.
And the whale goes underwater. And she's
down there for a long time. And then
they go after her with the boats and
everything. And eventually her body
floats up.
Sad story.
They do save her.
And in that moment, the grandfather
finally sees her for who she is. And
forgives her for what her father had
done.
That's the story of a man transformed.
We needed to see that. Because in
ourselves, we seed ourselves in the
character on the screen. Like we need to
learn to love and move beyond what
things look like, our prejudice and our
ideas about that. That's how you tell a
story. Does that make sense, everybody?
Okay, you got that? Okay, great. Okay,
that's storytelling. Okay?
Are we good? You got some ideas?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. What you need to do is you go on
the internet and you look for formats.
When you find something that works
structurally, you have to understand and
break it apart. Like, why does this
work?
They had a wide shot for the opening
scene. There was a um what what is
called a non sequitur, a random weird
moment that really hooked me.
And you get people involved in the
story. Okay? There's a guy, I forget his
name.
Uh he's a young guy. I think he's
American. He's white boy.
And he goes out into poor parts of
America or the world. Really poor parts.
And he pretends to be homeless. If
you've seen his content, you'll know
exactly what I'm talking about. He'll
sit on the floor
like this and he'll have dirty socks on.
And he'll wait outside of a supermarket
or something in a really poor part of
town. And somebody will come by, usually
a black person, he goes, "Um,
excuse me. Um, could you give me some
money so I can buy a pair of shoes?"
And he goes, "Ah." The person's like,
"Yes, what do you need?" "I just need a
pair of shoes." And he goes, "What's
happened to your life?" He goes, "You
know, I'm homeless. I'm just trying to
figure things out."
He goes, "Wait right here. What shoe
size are you?" He goes into the store.
He comes out. He gives him a pair of
shoes.
And he goes, "I got you some water and I
got you a sandwich." And the And the And
the guy's like really touched. He goes,
"Why would you do this for me?"
He goes, "You know what? I don't have a
lot myself. I I can't even pay rent, but
I know when somebody needs help, I'm
going to help them." Like right now I'm
like,
And you go into the whole thing like,
"Don't do it, Chris. Just don't do it.
It's just a video. I know it's a video."
It's staged for me. I know. Stop. Stop.
And I can't help myself.
Okay? And they get into this whole
dialogue. And he goes, "You know what?
I
I'm not poor. I'm not homeless.
I don't need this. Take this back." He
goes, "No, no, it's for you. It's for
you." He goes, "You know what?
I was just waiting for some the first
person to do a nice thing for me."
He goes, "You know what? Here. Here's a
thousand dollars." And the man's like,
"No, no." You know? And they're often
very religious. They're like, "Oh,
Jesus. I needed this money." They go
through this whole thing. I'm like, "Ah,
pull it together."
You [snorts] know, rocks and hammers.
Rocks and hammers. I got this.
Right? We can do this. And so all of a
sudden they're I'm hooked into the
story. And then he goes, "You know what?
Hold on. I got one more surprise for
you." He has a blue duffel bag. Brings
the duffel bag out. It's ten thousand
dollars now. He goes, "You know what?
Are you a fan of the blah blah blah
team?" And he goes, "Yes." He goes,
"You're going to have front row seats.
I'm going to take you. You know? And you
know what? We're going to go in this
car. That's your car." It was like, "It
doesn't stop."
>> [laughter]
>> It doesn't stop.
And I love this message because
it is great for people to do
random acts of generosity, random acts
of kindness.
So we so see so many negative things.
This young man has raised more money for
charity than any other content creator.
It's amazing.
So you have to find your story.
And that's a format that all of you can
use. There's a problem, there's
expectations, and the stakes get higher
and higher.
I give you it back. Here's a thousand,
here's 10,000, here's the car, here's
the tickets to the favorite game that
you've always wanted to go to. Actually,
I bought you a house.
It is amazing. Yes, he actually does
crazy things. Isn't it amazing? And you
know what happens? Companies give him
money.
So
we talk about things like the attention
economy. You guys know the attention
economy? You know this? Yes, okay. If
you don't know, just say I don't know.
Attention economy, okay?
I think there's something called the
thank you economy.
And I think it's cooler than the
attention economy. Attention feels empty
sometimes,
but the thank you economy is you do good
in the world with no expectations, and
we the audience thank you for it by
watching it, by supporting you. So when
these videos get 10 million views,
sometimes they get even more than that,
a corporate company will come in like,
"We like what you do, young man, young
lady.
How much money do Oh,
okay, Hyundai, you want to give us the
car? Cool. Um
Chicago Bulls tickets? Great."
Isn't it amazing? We can just do good
for other people, and because of the
views via social media, we can build
completely different kinds of
businesses.
I'll give you one more example. I I love
to share this example. There's a series
of videos that go around about people
doing really humble things, like
blue-collar stuff, not white-collar,
blue-collar, like washing the car,
mowing the lawn.
Um what else do they do? Uh washing the
rug. You seen these things? Carpet
cleaners? So what they do is they go to
a poor person and they mow the lawn
and it's out of control. And they're
working on for hours. Now, you think
they're okay, how long did this young
person work on mowing the lawn? Maybe 5
hours. At the rate in which blue collar
work is paid, what do you think they get
paid? 20 bucks an hour at most. So, he
might have made 100 150 bucks for that
day. But instead he helps someone,
usually an elderly person, usually a
poor person, he takes care of their lawn
and the video gets 2 million views. And
if you do the calculation of the CPM,
that's thousands of dollars, not to
mention the brand deals. So, he's not in
the lawn mowing business. He's in the
helping people business that
corporations then pay for, that we pay
for by watching. That is the thank you
economy. I share this with you because
many of you are locked into what you do
and what you sell. But if you make a
small pivot from what you do and what
you sell, you can have a completely new
business that's 100% aligned with who
you are.
And to me, that's the wealth that I want
to have. To be paid to help people.
Cuz I think I have the best job in the
world.
Yeah? You guys understand thank you
economy?
Okay. Beautiful. Let's have another
question. Thank you. Let's do this.
Another question.
>> Hello. Hi. I do AI and software
development and I have a huge challenge
niching down.
>> What's your challenge?
>> I don't know what niche to pick.
>> Have you tried?
>> Yeah. I tried education because that was
my previous business and it
was pretty [snorts] terrible because
most of coaches turns out they
don't make enough money for my services.
Okay. So, you tried education, it didn't
work out? Yes. How long did you try it
for?
A few months.
That's a good effort.
>> [laughter]
>> Are you married?
>> Yes.
>> Was it easy?
>> No.
>> How long did you try for?
>> Three years and going.
>> So, you really wanted her or him?
>> Yes.
>> No judgement.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, or they. Okay.
Uh so, three years was a good time. How
long would you have tried?
>> Forever.
>> Right, that's a good answer. Is she
here?
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Cuz I would say blink twice if you feel
safe.
Okay. I thought that was a lady I could
get. Don't look at me. Okay, fine. She's
not here.
That's sad.
She didn't want to be here?
>> She has a more successful business, so.
>> Good catch, bro. Good catch.
>> [laughter]
>> He was running fast after her cuz she
was running faster, but he eventually
caught her. Right?
>> Yeah.
>> I think that's how tigers eat deer. They
eventually get tired.
>> [laughter]
>> If you keep running.
>> I like that. You know, a side note here,
I have this theory. Are there any single
men here? Raise your hand.
Give it up for the single men.
>> [clears throat]
[laughter]
>> Oh my god, that was so sad. It was like,
single men.
>> [laughter]
>> Holy cow, no judgement. There's like
five single guys here. Any single women
here? Raise your hand. Let's hear it for
the single women.
Woo! Holy cow, hold on. Lower your
hands. Boys, pay attention. There's way
more of them than you.
This is called a seller's market.
Do you understand this?
My gosh, are you getting hit on at the
bar all the time?
See, in America we have to try really
hard. Here, you just stand.
>> [laughter]
>> No?
You shower and you stand, that's all you
need to do. Cuz there's like 200 to
five.
Is it true or not?
Yeah? Ladies, oh my god, it's a tough
job out there, huh?
Welcome to our world.
>> [laughter]
>> You have to get a personality.
You have to be charming, and you have to
be successful.
So, this guy will chase you. Okay. Well,
okay, what were we talking about?
Oh, 3 years and 3 months.
Do you really want it?
>> Yeah, for sure.
>> So, why did you stop?
Mhm.
So, I suspect Okay, go ahead. Sorry.
>> other niches where
like the need is higher because if
you're a coach and you have two or three
clients, you're not thinking about
automating and
doing all that.
>> Okay.
All right.
I mean,
every [clears throat] time somebody
tells me they want something and give
up, my argument is you don't really want
it.
Because I want something, you cannot
stop me.
You know that expression, if you don't
want to learn, you cannot be taught, but
if you want to learn, no one can stop
you?
>> Yep.
>> Okay, so some reason you don't want it
that much. That's okay.
That's okay, I'm not judging you. Okay?
I just happen to have the next slide,
it's called specialization.
It just worked out this way. Okay. Most
people suffer from the lack of clarity
about who they serve.
They try to serve too many people, and
when you serve too many people, you
serve no one.
You serve nobody. So, we got to pick,
and picking is kind of hard, and I'll
talk about that later, right? But,
specialization, in my opinion, now, feel
free to argue with me. Some of you guys
like to argue with me, and that's okay.
I find that almost everybody that I
know, with the exception of a very small
percent, the more specialized they
become, the more successful they become.
There is, I believe now, not just
correlation, but causation.
Who here is a generalist and is doing
really well, is just crushing it? Just a
couple of people. And who is a
specialist and is crushing it? Look
around the room. Look around the room.
There are I mean, there should be more
than that. Maybe some Everyone else is
in the middle. Okay?
>> Yeah, I I have another business and I
crush it because it's specialized.
>> And what's your problem then?
Is that a flex on us? You already got
the girl. You already got the girl.
>> No, like I want I want to do this thing
because
I resonate way more with it. It's just I
I look at my other business, I see how
well things work and how everything is
has a process, but in here it's like
super difficult to create it from
scratch because I don't know
>> Of course.
>> who to focus.
>> Yeah. Difficult things are worth having.
Easy things are not worth pursuing. You
pursued this woman for 3 years. She was
difficult. Did it work out?
>> Yep.
>> You don't have to say that, but yes. The
answer is yes, of course.
Okay, [clears throat] so here's what we
can do. You have a business that you're
crushing it in. You have this other
thing you want to do, it's called
education.
They're They don't have to be
one either or. You can do both.
So, you know that expression there's
your 9:00 to 5:00 and there's your 5:00
to 9:00?
Have you guys heard that?
What you do [clears throat] for your
money, 9:00 to 5:00. What you do for
your soul, 5:00 to 9:00.
You have more hours than you think.
Do you have kids?
>> No.
>> Good. And keep it that way for a little
bit.
No, for real. Having children
complicates everything. The cool thing
about you and your wife or your partner
is you can say, "Honey,
I need your support in this. I know you
make a lot more money than me, so you
understand.
But I'm all for feminism.
Is it okay if I be the wife for a little
bit and just work on my personal thing?
So, I'll do my part here, but I need
this extra time to do this other thing.
And I'm going to ask you for 2 years
where I get to explore this
cuz it's deep in my heart that I need to
make this work. I'm going to make a lot
of bad decisions along the way, but it's
a learning process.
Can I get your buy-in on this?
What would she say to that?
>> She already encourages me.
>> What?
>> Oh, I thought you said she already
divorced me.
>> No, no, no.
>> That was a pretty sad story. No wonder
the long face. Okay, so she So why did
you quit then?
>> I
I didn't. I'm still trying things. It's
just
I I feel I have this intuition that
there's a way better niche than
education or my automations.
>> All right. Have you read the book The
Dip by Seth Godin?
>> Uh no.
>> Okay, good. I've read it. I'll tell you
all about the book right now.
I'll tell you the whole book. And then
you should buy the book to support
authors and artists, okay? I'm not
trying to take money from people.
This is result.
Uh this is effort.
Okay, the longer the effort this is
greater result. I believe this is
effort, okay? In the beginning whenever
you try something new, it's not a lot of
effort and you get a lot of results.
When you start to post on social media,
in fact, the algorithm on most social
platforms rewards you when you're new.
Create a new account, you make a post,
it it goes it goes and it goes. And it's
pretty cool. And then it feels like
you've been shadowbanned and all of a
sudden it's like I'm not having a lot of
fun anymore. And over time I'm just
putting more and more effort and I'm
getting less and less result. And it
goes here.
And in here Seth calls it the dip. This
is the dip.
This is fun. I'm a happy boy, happy
girl. Everything's great. Down here it
just feels like so much work and it's no
longer fun.
So what do we do?
We quit.
We start again. We pick a new hobby.
What's your next business besides
education?
>> I teach people how to code and become
programmers.
>> So you're still teaching then?
>> Yes.
>> So that's working?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Let's pretend you said I became a
chef.
So Oh, it's so fun to cook. I'm making
great dishes and Oh god, it's getting
really hard again. It's getting really
hard again. We quit. And Seth says we do
this over and over again. We just quit
all the time. So you know what? Every
time you quit, you start over. Everybody
Anybody here do this? Does this sound
remotely Yeah, we're being honest with
each other, right? Yeah. So, what he
says is what we have to do is we have to
push beyond the dip. I know this is not
your question. I'm just going to use
this as a way to talk, okay? I got you.
Cuz I I see your eyes.
Okay? So, he says here it's really hard,
but all of a sudden there's this like
hockey stick growth where you do this
and it's like wah.
And everybody dies here.
Right before gold. Like that 3 ft from
gold. Just 3 more ft and you would have
found gold.
>> Yeah, my first business I didn't make
money for 2 years. And it's exactly like
what you drew.
>> Okay.
And they're like, "Woah, it's so hard."
See, I like things that are difficult
cuz it means there's less competition
cuz everybody quits here. So, if I am
just persistent and determined, I will
get that result.
And I've done this over and over again.
I'll give you an example, okay? I'll get
to your question eventually.
Okay?
Here's Here's the numbers if I can
remember it. Okay.
2014, start YouTube, okay?
Um
during this time I think we're between 4
to 5 million dollars in revenue
as a service design business called
Blind.
Okay? Initially, for the hardcore fans,
the company was called The School.
It was not called The Futur. And I was
doing it with my business partner back
then.
I think that first year we made 17,000
dollars.
17K versus 4 and 1/2 million dollars.
Year one, year two we made something
like 48,000 dollars.
Still not enough to hire anybody. This
is barely enough to pay for lunch
for the year.
So, this is usually where people quit.
They're done. But we keep sticking to
it. So, by the third year I think we're
at 150K. And I can only sort of remember
this because every year we would grow by
3X. And 3X growth is wild.
But if you only take into consideration
the first year was so terrible.
Right? So eventually the company becomes
a $4 million company
because we just keep doing this over and
over again.
Right? So this is
you and your primary business.
This is you and your secondary business.
And you can do this. I've done this so
many times. I'm not really talking about
you right now. I'm just talking about
everybody else. You want to get back to
niching, we'll talk about niching. Okay?
So the niching is People say it's so
difficult to niche, and I'm going to
show you how easy it is.
If you trust me. Do you trust me?
Will you do it?
It's okay. I'll pretend like you said
yes.
Everybody ask the question no one wants
to answer.
Okay.
Anybody here struggle with niching,
picking a niche? Great.
I have good news and I have even better
news for you. Okay? I'll I'll first
share the good news, okay? We're going
to draw a graph like this. Okay? That's
the graph. And these are dimensions,
okay?
People are like, "I can't pick. I can't
pick." I said, "Well, would you rather
work with men or women?"
And what would you say?
Who said both?
You're fired.
You have to pick one or the other. When
it's A or B, it's either A or B. It
can't be, "Well, let me think about it."
Okay? So some people prefer to work with
women, some people prefer to pick with
men. But in theory, if we're split, not
in this room, clearly 50/50, we've just
eliminated half the market. This is
pretty good. Now what we can do is we
can say, "Are they early in their
career? Are they middle? Are they late
in their career?" Was they early? Was
they middle? Are they late?
And what would you say then? Both.
Middle. Okay, so you you said men?
You prefer men.
What what what?
Okay, late. You didn't you say middle?
Pick one.
Late. Okay, this is good. So, how old
are they?
Perfect. I love this.
My my people.
40s and 50s, yes? Great. Serve us,
please. Okay, so this is your your
demographic now, okay? Notice how we've
eliminated most of the market already.
I've only asked two two questions.
It's not that hard. Okay, what's the
thing that makes the that's common to
these old dudes?
>> They don't know technology.
>> Oh, screw you. I know technology.
>> Sorry.
>> [laughter]
>> Some of them don't.
We're Gen Xers. We should know
technology. We grew up with some
internet.
Okay, so they're um
technophiles? No, what are they?
Uh what do we call these people?
Not technophiles, that's the opposite.
Neophytes.
Okay, they're they're bad with tech,
okay? And how do we know this?
Ooh, this is good marker.
Oh, it's so juicy.
I love it.
Bad tech. Okay, what else?
>> They know they need tech to be more
efficient in their business.
>> What kind of business?
>> Probably something more blue collarish.
Not necessarily a internet-first
business.
>> Okay, I like this. Like roofers,
electricians, that kind of stuff?
>> Yeah.
>> No, I don't believe you. That was a
pregnant yes.
What Tell me more. Blue collar what?
Like give me an example.
Yes? Give me an example.
>> Yeah, service-based businesses.
>> Like?
>> Like yeah, plumbers, electricians.
>> What I said before.
>> Yeah.
>> Did I convince you or you convinced
yourself? Okay.
>> me.
>> Okay.
He feels the heat.
Plumber, electrician. This is great. How
much money are they doing a year?
In revenue.
>> Seven figures.
>> Give me a more specific number.
>> Two
two five.
>> That's perfect. That that works for me.
Two to five million dollars in revenue.
Okay, so you can start to see now the
market got really specific. Do they live
in a specific region in the world?
>> US.
>> US. Where in the US?
>> Texas.
>> Okay.
>> Pretty good place. No, for real. There's
a lot of opportunities in Texas.
Okay?
All right.
Okay.
What problems do they have? Now we get
into like
solving their problems. So every morning
they wake up and they're like, "God, I
just wish this problem would go away."
What problems do they have?
>> Speed to lead contact.
>> Speed what?
>> Speed to lead like how fast
>> regular regular language here. Don't use
marketing language.
>> do you contact the lead once they
inquire?
>> Oh, I see. Okay. So they have So what do
we call that?
>> Responsiveness.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. So they have a challenge with
responsiveness and how are they getting
inquiries?
>> Probably they have some online presence
and Google Maps and that.
>> Like email?
>> Email, inquiry forms, website.
>> Okay, email, website, stuff like that.
It's perfect and this is ideally aligned
to what you do, right?
>> Yep.
>> Okay. So this is how you pick a niche.
You guys got that? It's not that hard.
The problem is we just don't want to
make decisions.
We really don't. It's hard.
A simple question of where would you
like to eat sends us into a 30-minute
discussion.
Yeah?
Okay, so what else do you need here to
pick your niche?
So you do educational content for
blue-collar people working in Texas
doing between two to five million
dollars.
>> Yeah, it's You helped me a lot.
>> I've helped you a lot?
>> Yeah.
>> What time?
Shoot. CG Eagle, this is how you do it.
Where are you? And he's gone. Okay.
Anyways, so what we can do is we need to
figure out our ICP, our ideal client
profile.
Okay? And a lot of people struggle with
this and I'll just tell you some hacks
to do this, okay? Think of the best
client you've ever had in your life.
They paid you a lot, they paid on time,
they're easy to work with, they made
decisions quickly, and there's a lot of
them.
Who are these people? Just look into
your history.
And make an educated guess. And here's
what we do. Okay, I'm going to freestyle
live prompt with you right now, okay? So
you're going to go on Claude, don't use
ChatGPT.
Go on Claude and say, um
uh I'll pretend I'm you. What's your
name?
>> Peter.
Uh 36?
>> 32.
Hey, um uh Claude, I'm 32, my name is
Peter. I provide tech solutions for this
specific demographic. And you describe
it. I need help in defining my ideal
client profile. Feel free to ask me a
few questions before you make a
suggestion. Be sure you check that
there's enough potential customers in
the market before you make this
recommendation.
See, the machinery knows all the
language.
It's much, much smarter than you in
terms of its data repository.
But when you activate certain keywords,
it understands. But when you start using
loose language, it doesn't know what to
do.
So sloppy input, sloppy output. Okay? So
use this term. You don't even have to
type in ideal client profile, you can
just say ICP. It knows.
And whatever it spits out, now use your
human brain to decide, does this ring
true? Does it survive the pressure test?
I have to check to see if it's true or
not. So sometimes it spits out something
not good.
I don't blame the machine, I blame you
because you gave it poor input. You gave
it conflicting data. You didn't ask it
to ask you clarifying questions.
We need to do that. Usually, I'm almost
a one or two shot prompter because my
prompts are very detailed and they're
very specific. Language does matter.
Okay? So, you describe it this way.
And then you should get your ICP. Then,
once you have an ideal client profile
really clearly defined, you can say now,
"What problems do they have that they'd
like to get rid of?"
And use the language that they would
use, not the language of marketing.
Cuz I want to hear it. So, they're going
to use things like, "I struggle with
this. I hate this." Those are all their
problems. Then you can even ask it,
"Rank, based on what you know, those
problems from top highest to lowest in
terms of how much pain it's causing them
and how much they're willing to pay to
make this problem go away."
And what might surprise you is you offer
none of those solutions.
This is an opportunity.
>> [music]